Dylan Shaw

dylanjshaw000@gmail.com | (508) 944-1304 | New York City NY

LINKS

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/dylan-j-shaw
- https://iamdylan.surge.sh/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am passionate about transforming business initiatives into modern web solutions. My experience in a technical consultative role (see Tealium) and as a developer on a fast paced Agile team (see BVAccel) have together taught me to carefully balance client needs with business constraints. I keep my code as simple, legible and reusable as possible. Technologies used should be best suited for the task at hand. I prefer to write in modern JS frameworks including ReactJS/VueJS, though I am comfortable learning any new framework or language as needed. Check out https://iamdylan.surge.sh/ for a more colorful summary.

WORK HISTORY

Oshen Inc.. New York City, NY
Full Stack Developer (contract) | 05/2020 - 04/2021

- Co-developed RESTful API in Node/Express for B2C text campaign tool.
- Built dashboard components using ReactJS + SCSS.

BVAccel. San Diego, CA Front-end Developer | 05/2019 - 03/2020

- Built Shopify sites and in-site components for various D2C e-commerce brands including Red Bull, Good American, Pit Viper, Freshly Picked, and BioClarity.
- Co-authored a new store boilerplate theme using Slate + GraphQL + VueJS + SCSS.
- Regularly held agile team meetings with designers, contract developers, project managers and client representatives.

Tealium. San Diego, CA Solutions Engineer | 05/2016 - 05/2019

 Led deployment of user tracking code and site performance tracking code for enterprise clients including Autonation, PVH, Pacific Gas &

SKILLS

- Technologies/Applications:
 JavaScript (ES5-7, TypeScript, vueJS, reactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, NextJS), HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS, Liquid, Apex, Gatsby, web APIs, SQL, AWS (RDS), Firebase, Asana, Zendesk, TealiumIQ
- Ecosystems: SaaS, e-commerce, Shopify, digital marketing/advertising, web analytics, stock derivatives
- Technical writing & speaking
- Product & brand advocacy
- Client retention & relationship building
- Workflow optimization & internal tooling

EDUCATION

University of San Diego San Diego, CA 2016

Bachelor of Science: Behavioral Neuroscience & Philosophy Academic Advisor, Delta Tau Delta fraternity, Theta Zeta chapter

- Electric, Deckers, and Charter.
- Developed custom tag integrations for analytics vendors including Google, Omniture/Adobe, Facebook, Reddit, and Yahoo.
- Developed ad hoc extensions of and bug fixes for Tealium core library on a per-client basis.
- Hosted live tutorials to train clients on how to best leverage Tealium software to achieve their business goals.
- Co-authored a tribal knowledge base for Customer Success department to document workarounds for bugs in vendor code; this improved our project turnaround by preventing unnecessary rewrites of the same solutions.
- Developed a Zendesk widget app that automatically delegated projects to members of my team in randomized fashion; this solved a project coverage problem we were experiencing when employees were leaving the office on holiday.
- Refactored, consolidated and contributed to my team's internal UI
 toolset; these tools improved our workflow by automating some
 processes, reducing total number of clicks, and making our product
 more aesthetically appealing; many of these tools were and continue
 to be integrated into the product.